Teuku Lukman Nur Hakim

Project Controller, Mobile: +62815-8053-224

Jalan Ketapang no.4 Perum Harapan Kita, Karawaci, Tangerang

Email: teuku.lukman.nur.hakim@gmail.com

Overview

A multi-skilled professional with a good track record of managing multiple projects and developing new processes and systems. An enthusiastic, proactive, initiative, flexible individual and a good team player willing to take full responsibility for the delivering of project objectives and targets on time, on scope, on budget and meeting the desired quality.

Skills/Expertises/Interests

Knowledge Management ● Project Control Management ● Detailed planning, scheduling and organizing ● Progress Reports ● Risk Identification and Analysis ● Project Coordination

Quality Management ● Change Management ● New System/Process Development

Data Analysis and Recommendation ● Persuasive Communication

Negotiation ● Project Problem Solver ● Project Mover

Professional Experience

PT. Indosat Tbk

Jakarta, Indonesia

The fastest mobile network and fastest 4G network provider with 68,5 millions subscribers by 2015 in Indonesia offering a channel of communication for mobile phone users with brand selling Matrix Ooredoo, Mentari Ooredoo and IM3 Ooredoo, other services provided are a communication channel via voice for fixed telephone (fixed) including international direct dialing IDD (international direct Dialing) and MIDI (Multimedia, Internet & Data Communication Services).

Project Controller Office of President Director & CEO

December 2015 – Present

Overseeing & supporting various projects, programs and initiatives requested by BoD to ensure those are implemented and meet the goals.

Selected Accomplishment:

- Full support and involvement in partnership with Qlue and Aksaramaya to create new product bundling called Smart City offered to Municipality in Indonesia and launched first in Pekanbaru
- Full support and involvement in launching a new program for Indosat mobile money registration & services through existing outlets in Sukabumi as a pilot project approved by Bank Indonesia before implemented in other cities
- Full support and involvement in developing and launching yearly event of Indosat Ooredoo Stock Trading Competition (ISTC) in corporation with Trimegah & Bursa Efek Indonesia
- Full support and involvement in preparation and coordination of launching Program Keluarga Harapan (PKH) in corporation with Bank Mandiri to support the Indonesia Government in distributing the donation via mobile number registered e money
- Conceptualized and implemented Indosat internship program for undergraduate students

Duties:

- Analyzing and consolidating the yearly budget of CEO Directorate
- Analyzing and monitoring realization of yearly budget
- Exploring & evolving the BoD direction in order to be well accepted by the related business units
- Facilitating and managing cross-functional discussion & meetings both internal and external
- Determining project resource availability & allocation
- Coordinating with various divisions to support the project / initiatives requested by BOD
- Tracking & providing various project progress status, next actions, PIC & deadline

- Identifying and escalating issues and risks that may impact overall target
- Providing reports defining the project progress, problems and offered solutions
- Preparing project approval documentation, internal memo & business requirement draft if needed
- Proposing the initial draft for business process or workflow

PT. Mora Telematika Indonesia Tbk (Moratelindo) Jakarta, Indonesia

Moratelindo is a wholesale telecom infrastructure company which has International submarine backbone infrastructure network and national backbone infrastructure network, as well as eleven Nusantara Data Center (NDC) to support and provide telecommunication solutions such as Connectivity Services, Internet Services, Data Center and Value Added Services.

Assistant Head of PMO

May 2015 – December 2015

Assisting the Head of PMO in managing & setting up PMO Processes for FTTH (Fiber To The Home) new roll out projects

Reporting To: Report to FTTH Project Director & Head of PMO

Key Accomplishment:

- Full support and involvement in achievement 21.672 Homes passed
- Created project progress dashboard for management report
- Created PMO Database for FTTH Project
- Created FTTH Project Timetable
- Defined OLT (Optical Line Terminal) Site Infrastructure Timetable
- Defined and proposed Project Cycle and Business Process including SLA (Service Level Agreement) for every activities
- Proposed a new process to do technical survey by internal to speed up the process from one week become two days
- Defined and proposed responsibility matrix for each department related to FTTH Project
- Proposed and involved in creating business process for BAST Document Completeness, Standardization of FTTH Network & Operation Handover Document Completeness
- Defined FTTH Project guideline principles for solving existing issues

Duties:

- Ensuring and reporting project progress to FTTH Project Director
- Analyzing project progress and doing follow up actions
- Managing and monitoring multiple projects from Sales Feasibility, Technical Feasibility, Design Process, Construction and Home Pass Management
- Managing and monitoring OLT (Optical Line Terminal) Site Infrastructure Progress from Site Survey, Material Estimation, Sitac, Administration Process, Tendering, Material Order, CME & ME Works, Installation, commissioning, Integration & Test Service
- Initiating and leading a meeting for finding solutions (Project progress and Issues, Standardization and Business Process)
- Leading and presenting weekly progress & issue meeting to management and all related divisions
- Leading five persons to do technical survey
- Directing and recommending to the network designers in order to design network according to technical survey
- Monitoring FTTH Project material from PR (Purchase Request), PO (Purchase Order) and Delivery material to Vendors
- Handling Project Issues & bottlenecks (Permit, Network Design and Material) and proactively identifying solutions and coordinating to related dept/div in order to ensure the project progress
- Registering and tracking project issues & risks for weekly meeting and proposing solution, PIC and deadline
- Gathering of project data for management review
- Updating PMO Database
- Giving guidance, recommendation and solution for Project Bottleneck and Improvement
- Acting as the overall advocate for FTTH project management

PT. LinkNet Tbk (First Media)

Jabodetabek, Indonesia

Group of companies as a Lippo Group subsidiaries is the largest provider of high speed broadband internet, cable pay TV, and high-speed data communication services.

Assistant Project Manager

November 2012 – April 2015

Assisting the Project Manager in managing the day-to-day operations of the network construction project including planning, directing, coordinating activities of designated project and handling project issues to ensure the project objectives and targets are accomplished on time, on scope, on budget and on the desired quality.

Reporting To: Report to New Roll Out (NRO) Director & Construction Divison Head

Key Accomplishment:

- Full support and involvement in NRO first guarter achievement 56.707 Homes Passed in 2015
- Full support and involvement in NRO yearly achievement 238.135 Homes Passed in 2014
- Full support and involvement in NRO yearly achievement 260.537 Homes Passed in 2013
- Designed and created prioritization system for Survey, Costing and Design Coax & Fiber Optic
- Significantly increased the productivity of issued complete document in line with project target
- Developed and documented Risk Identification and Analysis
- Drastically reduced the number of project issues by creating check list of completeness of documents before stepping into construction progress
- Initiated GPS Projects for ICON+ Report
- Defined and implemented some new arrangements with other dept/div regarding the increase in the project progress speed
- Designed and created monitoring system for substitution and additional material request during the construction progress
- Compiled FTTH Implementation Reference Book
- Defined NRO Project Management Application Workflow

Duties:

- Ensuring and reporting project progress to NRO Director
- Analyzing project progress and doing follow up actions
- Managing and monitoring multiple projects from Permit Done, Survey, Design Coaxial & Fiber Optic, Costing, Document Approval, Construction and Activation Progress
- Defining priority list and scheduling for Survey, Design & Costing Phase
- Providing information & data to stakeholders regarding project including contractor assignment, schedule, progress, status, risks, cost, reinstatement, check list, BAST and Handover.
- Directing and recommending to the network designers in order to design according to technical meeting agreement with developer & community representatives
- Monitoring and coordinating with permit team regarding permit issue/progress
- Checking the accuracy of network design drawing, Cost Estimation (CE) and Material Request (MR) for complete document approval
- Ensuring all project handover to Contractors are ready to construct
- Identifying and analyzing Project Risks
- Handling Project Issues & bottlenecks (Permit, Network Design, Network Configuration, Material, Construction Technical, Fiber Optic Access, Contractor and PLN Connection) and proactively identifying solutions and coordinating to related dept/div in order to ensure the project progress
- Escalating promptly any big issues that may impact overall target
- Requesting to redesign/reboundary/reroute of the network design if needed
- Requesting to add and substitute materials for areas high risk if needed
- Managing and monitoring PLN Connection & Fiber Optic Status
- Maintaining cost per home under 116 \$
- Defining justification letter for project initiation and completion outside the standard budget

Management Development Program

January 2012 – October 2012

Identifying key business issues and solutions that are necessary to be successful in developing and increasing bussiness unit, Department or Division Performance.

Key Accomplishment:

- Designed Hub Configuration for Forward and Reverse System
- Achieved in maintaining 95% of HFC network areas with SNR (Signal Noise Ratio) level above 25 dB
- Designed and created new standard format for sourcing summary with database and new performance features by using macro excel programming
- Designed and created master plan of vendor portal in collaboration with IT Team
- Developed and added new features and capabilities in Purchase Request Online System in collaboration with IT Team
- Risk Assessment Summary and Recommendation for Warehouse Management, HFC Maintenance Division and Installation Division

Duties:

- First Project : Hub Configuration and SNR Improvement
- Second Project : Process Automation and SCM Strategic System
- Third Project : Development and Implementation of Risk Assessment

Academic Qualifications

M.Sc in Industrial Engineering with Specialization Quality and Environmental Management **2011,Graduate School of Engineering, University of Borås (Borås ,Sweden)**

Bachelor Degree in Department of Physics Engineering

2010, Undergraduate Faculty of Engineering, Gadjah Mada University (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

Trainings/Courses

Project Management, Lean Management, Time Management for Productivity, 8 Habits for Productivity, Fundamental Coaching, Powerful Negotiation Skills, Powerful Presentation Skills, Leading Effective Meeting, Communication Skills

Computer Skills

Ms Word, Ms Excel, Ms Power Point, Ms Project, SPSS, Minitab, AutoCAD, MatLab, Fluent, Bentley, Corel Draw and Photoshop